

COMPUTER SCIENCE STUDENT

Kongeslusen 11, 2610 Rødovre, Denmark

🖪 (+45) 2095-7574 🖾 carlorosso02@gmail.com 🏫 https://danesinoo.github.io 🗘 danesinoo 🛗 carlo-rosso-bb8b1820a

About me ___

I started my Master's degree in Computer Science in September. I am passionate about Machine Learning and Computer Science, indeed I completed a very interesting intership on NLP and sentiment analysis and I have loved it! Mainly because I was able to study and understand how some super cool algorithms work. I consider myself incredibly curious and motivated. I am also a socialist, therefore I am very interested in the Open Source world and I think Europe should invest more in it. I am looking for a two-year position, as I am still exploring whether I would like to continue working in the industry or pursue a PhD after completing my Master's.

Professional Experience

Machine Learning Intern

Padua (PD), Italy

University of Padua

07/2024 - 08/2024

- Worked on NLP with Scikit-learn, Numpy, Stanford Parser, and HuggingFace.
- Studied the literature on **sentiment analysis** with **SST-5** dataset.
- Implemented and compared machine learning algorithms (Kernel Methods, RNN, LLMs)

Front Office Assistant Padua (PD), Italy

University of Padua 08/2023 - 11/2023

- Responsabilities included data processing support, front office tasks, and archiving.
- 200h collaboration with Studenti Career Office.
- Selected by merit for a **part-time studenti collaboration**.

Mechanical Worker Motta di Livenza, Italy

• Fabricated and assembled automated machines, by cutting, shaping and preparing metal parts according to project specifications.

Education _____

TPA SRL

Master of Science in Computer Science

Copenhagen, Denmark

University of Copenhagen

09/2024 - ongoing

06/2019 - 07/2019

- I am focusing on Machine Learning, and I also like Advanced Programming.
- GPA: Not available yet.

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Padua, Italy

University of Padua

09/2021 - 09/2024

- Thesis: "Comparison of Kernel Methods and Large Language Models in Sentiment Analysis."
- Final Grade: 106/110.
- GPA: 3.5

Exchange Student RØDKILDE GYMNASIUM

Vejle, Denmark

08/2019 - 05/2020

- One year in Denmark as an exchange student.
- Focused on Mathematics, Physics, and Chemistry.
- The year of the COVID-19 pandemic.

Projects _____

Somebody's Blog! Personal Project

Anywhere in the world

2023 - ongoing

• Personal blog where I write my daily thoughts and experiences and todos.

2024-10-31 Carlo Rosso · Résumé

- Technologies: Markdown, Rust, GitHub Pages.
- Built the infrastructure which converts the markdown files into static HTML and deploys them to GitHub Pages seemlessly and automatically.

Easy Meal Padua, Italy

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, UNIVERSITY OF PADUA

2023 - 2024

- **Web application** designed to streamline restaurant reservations and order management for both customers and restaurateurs.
- Collaborated in a team of developers (6 students), following the **Model-View-Controller (MVC)** architectural pattern.
- Implemented backend using Node.js and Nest.js, managing restaurant data, orders, and user authentication.
- Implemented **frontend** using **Angular**, ensuring a responsive and user-friendly interface, with the same backend's design pattern: the **dependency-injection**.
- Employed **PostgreSQL** as the database and utilized **Drizzle ORM** for efficient interaction with the database and for experimenting with the new technology.
- Deployed the application using **Docker**, creating a containerized environment for easy development and deployment.
- **Evaluation**: 25/30.

Music vs Robot Padua, Italy

OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING, UNIVERSITY OF PADUA

2022

- Designed and developed a tower-defense-style game inspired by Plants vs Zombies using C++14 and the Qt framework.
- Clear separation of concerns with distinct layers for the game's logic (model) and graphical interface (view) to enhance maintainability and scalability.
- Applied key **object-oriented principles** such as encapsulation, polymorphism, and modularity to create an elaborate class hierarchy.
- Evaluation: 3/3 with honors.

Skills _____

Machine Learning NLP, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy, HuggingFace

Programming Functional Programming, Algorithms, Git, Object-Oriented Programming, Data

Structures, Database, Web Development

Programming Python, Haskell, Rust, C++, C, TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, Golang, SQL, Html, Typst,

Languages LaTex, Lua, Java, Matlab

Spoken Languages _____

Italian Native

English Fluent, **IELTS 7.5**, Strong in listening and reading, Working on writing

Danish Learning, Basic

Latin Only reading, Love the poetry

Interests _

Sports Judo, **Sailing**, Skiing, Climbing

Hobbies Open Source, Curiosity, Reading, 3D Modeling, Music, Cooking, Small-talk